Summary



Full-stack web developer with 5+ years of professional experience in education, marketing and agency environments. Proficient at troubleshooting, debugging and performing tasks to completion with little direction. Motivated and enthusiastic team player dedicated to improving processes and seizing all opportunities to learn new languages, tools and technologies.

Education



Bachelor of Science in Digital Arts & Design

Full Sail University, Winter Park, Florida

May 2007 – February 2009 Valedictorian and Advanced Achiever

Game Development

Full Sail University, Winter Park, Florida

January 2006 – May 2007
Transferred to Digital Arts & Design

Experience



Web Developer September 2009–present

Full Sail University, Winter Park, Florida

- Developed internal web applications for tracking alumni and their jobs, credits and awards, controlling the custom
 YouTube Channel, monitoring and flagging spam leads and returning leads for a specified period of time in case of a
 service outage
- Developed MVC frameworks for LMS 2.0, .edu desktop and mobile sites and Full Sail's 2012 W3 Gold award-winning custom YouTube Channel, using FuseBox, ColdFusion and xml-based CMS, Alfresco
- Implemented and modified APIs for internal applications and .edu desktop and mobile sites
- Developed landing pages using HTML, CSS and JavaScript, implementing them in LiveBall as necessary
- Developed WordPress custom theme back-end for fullsailblog.com
- · Performed bi-weekly deployments in load-balanced, multi-server environments for .edu desktop and mobile sites
- · Encouraged and facilitated transfer of all marketing projects from SVN to Git
- · Performed general site maintenance, content updates and bug fixes for all marketing sites associated with Full Sail
- Trained team members how to develop landing pages in LiveBall

Web Developer January 2009–present

Freelance, Winter Park, Florida

· Created websites for clients using HTML/CSS/JavaScript and WordPress

Graphic/Web Designer January 2009 - September 2009

Technetium Creative, Maitland, Florida

- $\bullet \ \, \text{Designed and developed sites and eBlasts for clients using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and ASP CMS DotNetNuke}$
- Created brochures, direct mailers, promotional items, newsletters, magazine advertisements, rack cards, business cards, logos, icons, debit cards and signage for clients

Graphics Intern November 2008 - January 2009

Worldwide Brands, Maitland, Florida

• Created banners and icons and aided in the redesign/development of the Worldwide Brands website

Skills



Programming Languages

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ColdFusion, PHP, Ruby

Frameworks/ CMS

FuseBox, Framework One, Alfresco, WordPress, Rails

Concepts/ Processes

MVC, OOP, ORM, Debugging, Deployments, htaccess/mod_rewrite, API Implementation, Responsive Web

Data Storage

XML, JSON, MySQL, MSSQL

Libraries

jQuery, Bootstrap, AngularJS

Apps/Tools/Programs

Adobe Creative Suite, Sublime Text, Coda 2, Git/SVN, Jira, Bugzilla, LiveBall, Basic Bash/Terminal